NAVINKS



Contact

Address:

Sunandh, Tc 43/78, Tollgate Junction, Thottam, Manacaud P.O, Trivandrum: 695009

Phone:

+91-9995120967

Email:

navinsivendran@gmail.com

LinkedIn Profile:

linkedin.com/in/navin-sivendran-49358048

Other Information

Experience in years: 9 years

Age: 34

Date of Birth: 14 - 02 - 1986

Summary

Machine Learning Engineer mainly focused in creating predictive models, especially in classification. Experienced with almost all stages of the development cycle for machine learning projects. Integrated models into our production pipeline for real-time processing. Adapted existing models to better handle problems specific to our domain. Strong background in project management and customer relations.

Experience

Quinoid Business Solutions

Duration: 18 January 2019 – Till Date Designation: Machine Learning Engineer

> College of Engineering, Guindy, Anna University

Duration: July 2016 - Till Date

Designation: Research Scholar (Ph.D. in Computer Science and

Engineering):

In the area of "Knowledge Mining from Clinical Data using

Machine Learning and Evolutionary Approaches".

➤ LBS Institute of Technology for Women, Poojappura, Thiruvananthapuram

Duration: 14 December 2012 - 13 May 2016

Designation: Assistant Professor

Worked as Assistant Professor, in Computer Science and Engineering at LBS Institute of Technology for Women,

Poojappura.

Designed and Implemented the College Website

http://lbsitw.ac.in/using Joomla framework and Mysql.

➤ ISEC School of Engineering and Consultancies

Duration: January 2012 - December 2012

Designation: Senior Faculty

Worked as a Senior Faculty and Trainer.

Media and Entertainment Ltd

Duration: 10 January 2010 - 29 August 2010

Designation: Tech Support

Worked as a Technical Support at Media and Entertainment

HCL info systems Ltd

Duration: 8 November 2008 - 23 October 2009

Designation: Faculty Engineer

Worked as a Faculty Engineer and a Trainer.

Area of Interest

- 1. Machine Learning
- 2. Artificial Intelligence
- 3. Deep Learning
- 4. Data Science
- 5. Data Mining
- 6. Evolutionary Algorithms
- 7. Cloud Compouting
- 8. Internet of Things

Programming Strengths

1. Python: Intermediate

2. R: Intermediate

3. Matlab: Intermediate

4. Php: Intermediate

5. Mysql: Intermediate

Python Libraries

- 1. TensorFlow
- 2. Scikit-Learn
- 3. Numpy
- 4. Keras
- 5. PyTorch
- 6. SciPy
- 7. Theano
- 8. Pandas
- 9. Numpy
- 10. Tesseract
- 11. Flask

Database

1. SQL: Intermediate

2. MySQL: Intermediate

3. PostgreSQL: Intermediate

4. Microsoft SQL: Intermediate

5. MongoDB: Beginner

Tools

1. R Tool: Intermediate

2. Joomla Framework: Intermediate

Education

> Ph.D. in Computer Science & Engineering (Part-time)

July 2016 - Till Date

Anna University, Chennai Research Scholar

Ramanujan Computing Centre College of Engineering, Guindy

> M.Tech. in Computer Science & Engineering

July 2010 - June 2012

Anna University, Chennai Specialization: Computer Science

Vel Tech Multi Tech Dr.Rangarajan Dr.Sakunthala Engineering College, Avadi, Chennai - 600062

> B.Tech. in Computer Science & Engineering

June 2004 - July 2008

University of Kerala Specialization: Computer Science

Marian Engineering College, Kazhakuttom Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala - 695582

➤ Higher Secondary (+2)

June 2002 - July 2004

Kerala Higher Secondary Board Specialization: Science

Model Boys higher Secondary School, Thycaud Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala - 695014

SSLC June 2002

Kerala State Board Specialization: General

St Mary's Higher Secondary School, Pattom Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala - 695004

Projects Undertaken (Academic)

Point of Sale Billing [B.Tech Mini Project]

Point of sale billing can be defined as billing software which will generate the bill for the particular customer at the time of purchase. Implemented this project in VC++ which consists of all the major concepts of oop.

Projects Undertaken (Academic)

Person Identification Using RFID [B.Tech Main Project]

A person identification using RFID scheme implements project which consists of an RFID tag which stores all the details of the customer including his image. When we scan this RFID tag by means of a scanner it will retrieve all the data from that tag and displays the result. Implemented this project in .NET 2.0 in Visual Studio 2005.

Parallel Processing in Cloud Computing [M.Tech Main Project]

Cloud computing mainly implies the major technologies in recent history which explains the various parallel processing techniques and job scheduling process for reducing the execution time for the cloud computing. Implemented this project in JAVA NETBEANS.

Papers Published

IJSER

Utilizing AES & Xor Encryption scheme for enhancing Data Security & Promoting Data Auditability in Cloud

IJRASET

Digital Signature & Advanced Standard for Enhancing Data Security & Authentication in Cloud Computing

IJSR

Dual Security using Dual Encryption schemes and efficient User Revocation in Cloud

Presentations Undertaken

- > Presented a paper on 'Human Computer Interface Using Face as Mouse' in a national conference held at Vel tech multi Tech College of engineering
- Presented a paper on "Reducing Execution Time in Cloud Using Parallel Processing" at S.A Engineering College
- ➤ Presented a paper on "Enabling Smart Personalized Health Care Using Mobile Data Cloud Integrating Intelligent Sensors" at L B S College of Engineering
- Presented a paper on "A Survey on Various Encryption Techniques for Enhancing Data Security in Cloud" at Heera College of Engineering &Technology
- Presented a paper on "Multi Keyword Ranked Search and Dual Security on Cloud Data Using Homomorphic Encryption" at Maria College of Engineering & Technology 29th March'2015 at Thiruvananthapuram organized by IFERP-India.
- Presented a paper on "Trusted Support and Otp Method for Moving Big Data to Cloud" Inter- national Conference on Emerging Trends in Engineering and Technology (ICET-15) held on 29th March'2015 at Trivandrum organized by IFERP-India.
- Presented a paper on "Anonymization Using MapReduce Algorithm with Secured Storage Service in Data Cloud" IEEE journal in an International Conference on Emerging Trends in Engineering, Business and Disaster Management [ICBDM 2015] held on 27 & 28th February 2015, at Noorul Islam University, Kumaracoil, Tamilnadu.

Workshops and Conferences

- Attended an FDP program at IIT Madras on the topic called "Pedagogical Training" organized by IIT Madras.
- ➤ Attended a Faculty Orientation Programme 'SAGHE-2015' organized by IIT Madras.
- Attended a workshop on 'Big Data Analytics' conducted by NIT Trichy
- Attended a workshop on 'Implementation of IPV6' conducted by Engineering Staff College of India
- Attended a workshop on 'Network Security Administration' organized by Engineering Staff College of India, Hyderabad (ESCI).
- Attended a workshop on 'Web site Administration Using Php and Mysql' conducted by Engineering Staff College of India
- Has participated in the Workshop on Cyber Forensics conducted as a part of IEEE International Symposium on Education, Technology and Entrepreneurship (ISEE) at Amrita Viswavidya Peetham, Kollam.
- ➤ Has successfully participated in Continuing Professional Development Programme on Network Security Administration at Engineering Staff College of India, Hyderabad.
- > Has officiated as Publicity Co-Chair in ICCSC held at Thiruvananthapuram organized by LBSITW.
- Participated in a National Conference on Advances in Computational Intelligence and Communication Technologies 2013 organized by LBS Institute of Technology for Women, TVM.
- Attended a Faculty Development Programme on Image Processing titled "Threads of Image Processing and its Applications" under TEQIP-II organized by Department of CSE, LBS Institute of Technology for Women, TVM.
- ➤ Has participated in the TEQIP-II sponsored Faculty Development Programme on Compiler Design & Optimization Techniques, LBS Institute of Technology for Women, TVM.
- Completed a Short Term Training Programme on Cloud Computing- It's benefits and modern trends under TEQIP-II at LBS Institute of Technology for Women.
- > Completed a Short term training Programme on Wireless Networks- Research Issues and Applications under TEQIP-II at LBS Institute of Technology for Women.
- > Completed a Short term training Programme on Topics in Theoretical Computer Science under TEQIP-II at LBS Institute of Technology for Women
- > Completed a Short term training Programme on Number theory and Cryptography under TEQIP- II at LBS Institute of Technology for Women.
- Completed a Short term training Programme on Data Structures & Algorithm Design Techniques" by Department of Computer Science at LBS Institute of Technology for Women
- > Successfully coordinated in 2 days Programme on ANDROID Workshop Robotics held at LBS Institute of Technology for Women.
- > Attended a workshop on 'Image Processing' conducted at Vel Tech Multi Tech College, Chennai.
- Attended a workshop on 'Python Programming' organized by Mar Baselious College of Engineering, Trivandrum under CSI chapter.
- Attended an innovative conference on 'Advanced Computing Applications' organized by Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai.

Responsibilities Undertaken

- ➤ Web Site Administrator: Created and designed the College Website and taken the role of Website Administrator
- CSI Chapter Co-ordinator: Co-ordinator in CSI chapter LBSITW
- Publicity Co Chair: Officiated as the Publicity Co-Chair at ICCSC-14
- Logo Developer: Created a logo for the Technical Incubation Cell (TBI)
- Co-ordinator: Co-ordinated a Workshop on "Data Structures and Algorithms"
- Co-ordinator: Coordinated a One day Workshop on "Intellectual Property Rights"
- Co-ordinator: Coordinated Two day Workshop on "Renaissance in Education"

Projects Undertaken

Apart from creating various Proof of Concepts (PoC) the other set of projects underwent are:

- Early Detection of Alzheimer's Disease Using Deep Learning Techniques [2019]
- Bank Cheque OCR Using Deep Learning Techniques [2020]
- Object Detection form Thermal Imaging (Video) using Convolutional Neural Networks [2020]
- > Air Quality Index prediction using Deep Learning Techniques using time series data [2020]
- Personality Prediction by analyzing Twitter Streams [2020]
- Enhanced Data anonymity for Privacy preservation in Cloud [2014-2015]
- Trusted Platform Service and OTP method for Moving Big Data to Cloud [2015-2016]
- Secured Multimedia Processing in Big data Using Data Cloud and MapReduce Algorithm [2016]
- Safe drive assist using Internet of Things [2016-2017]
- Automation of verification of design data for launch vehicle software [2016-2017]

Declaration

I hereby declare that all the information stated above are correct as per my knowledge.